RYOTARO NISHIDA

Pianist | Music Educator



Personal

Date of birth:

March 31, 1993

Nationality:

Japanese

Relationship:

Unmarried

Contact

Address:

401 Simfonia Setas, Kamayacho 26, Hodogaya, Yokohama, Kanagawa, 240 - 0062, Japan

Phone:

+8170 - 8537 - 1158

Email:

yusuzumi721@gmail.com

Languages

Japanese |
French |
English |



Summary

A classically trained pianist proficient in both solo and ensemble performances. A competent and experienced music educator with an eye for musical detail and the ability to personalise lessons that cater to the needs and interests of each individual student. Seeking to obtain a position that offers both a challenge and opportunity for growth to benefit knowledge learnt and experience earned alongside professionals. For the last 7 years, I have been teaching piano for students aged 3 - 50. Accomplished in building trust and relationships between students, parents, and administrators.

Education

Diplôme Suprieur d'Exécution (Advanced Piano)

École Normale de Musique Conservatory, Paris

- Major in Classical Piano Performance
- Studied with Professor Guigla Katsarava

Master's degree in Music Education

National Niigata University, Japan

- Received Monbukagakusho Honors Scholarship
- Major in Classical Piano Performance/Music education of Piano
- Studied with Professor Kenta Suzuki
- Performed Schumann's Symphonic Etude in his final concert

Bachelor of Music Art

National Niigata University, Japan

- Major in Classical Piano Performance
- Elected Chairperson for Music and Arts Course

Experience

Concert Pianist and Music Accompanist

- Free lance April 2015 ~ present
 - Solo recitals and performances with other musicians
 - Provide musical support to any variety of places

Music Teacher

- Kawasaki Tsuchihashi Elementary School May 2021 ~ present
 - Planning and executing music theory, music history and performance lessons
 - Providing instrument-specific education to students in one-onone and ensemble

Private Piano Teacher

- Piano class (Paris, France & Yokohama, Japan)
 - December 2017 ~ present
 - Structure weekly classroom music theory lesson plans
 - Educate students of all ages on effective piano technique, with focus on the Classical repertoire

Student Teacher (Music course)

- Niigata University, Japan September 2015 ~ March 2017
 - Facilitated instruction and learning activities for Music classes.
 - Gained strong foundation in classroom management and teaching principles

Certifications

Teacher's License (High school)
Teacher's License (Junior high school)

Skill Highlights

- Classical concert pianist
- Talented accompanist
- Extensive performance background
- Dedicated music teacher
- Comprehensive knowledge of music theory
- · Great communication skill

Awards

- 2019 France, Chateau International Piano Competition (2nd Prize)
- 2017 Niigata Music Competition Excellence Award
- 2016 Tokyo International Piano Competition Encouragement Award (2nd Prize)
- 2015 Yamagata Prefecture Rookie Concert Award (Passed the audition and appeared in the concert)
- 2015 Chopin International Piano Competition College Student Category Bronze Prize
- 2010 Yamagata Piano Concours Gold Prize and Prefectural Governor's Award

Concerts & Recitals

- Piano and Flute Recitals with Shiho Iwai, Yokohama, Japan in 2023
- Duo Recitals with Keisuke Konno, Yokohama, Japan in 2023
- Piano and Cello Recitals with Chihiro Ajiki, Tokyo, Japan in 2022
- Piano Duo Concert with Satsuki Fujishima, Tokyo, Japan in 2022
- Violin and Flute with Piano Concert at Takai Gunyakusho Hall, Nagano, Japan in 2022
- Duo Concert with Keisuke Konno at Bunnshokann Gijyo Hall, Yamagata, Japan in 2022
- Piano Concert at Tomioka Opa Hall, Yamagata, Japan in 2021
- Recital de Piano Eglise de Pantimont, Paris, France in 2019
- Concert Midi et Demi at Cortot Hall, Paris, France in 2019
- Piano Duo Concert with Anja Bramovic at Pantimont Church, Paris, France in 2019
- Piano Duo Concert with Bruno Teneos at Erik-Satie Conservatory, Paris, France in 2018
- Yusuzumi Piano Trio Concert, Yamagata, Japan in 2017
- Supring Concert at Daishi Hall, Niigata, Japan in 2017
- Primura Concert, Niigata, Japan in 2017
- Niigata Classic Concert, Niigata, Japan in 2016
- La Fille' Piano Concert, Niigata, Japan in 2016